A Finding Aid to the Chuck and Jan Rosenak Research Material, circa 1938-2003, in the Archives of American Art AAA.rosechuc
Archives of American Art
Chuck and Jan Rosenak research material
circa 1938-2003
AAA.rosechuc
Archives of American Art
17.6 Linear feet
The Chuck and Jan Rosenak research material dates from circa 1938-2003 and measures 17.6 linear feet. The collection contains research files for four books by the Rosenaks and includes letters, writings, notes, printed matter, tape-recorded interviews with artists, and photographic material.
Chuck Rosenak
Biographical Note
Chuck and Jan Rosenak are widely regarded as authorities in the field of American folk art. They amassed one of the finest collections of contemporary folk art in the United States and authored four books: Museum of American Folk Art Encyclopedia of Twentieth-Century American Folk Art and Artists (New York: Abbeville, 1990), The People Speak: Navajo Folk Art (Flagstaff, Arizona: Northland Publishing, 1994), Contemporary American Folk Art: A Collector's Guide (New York: Abbeville, 1996), and The Saint Makers: Contemporary Santeras y Santeros (Flagstaff, Arizona: Northland Publishing, 1998).
Scope and Content Note
The Chuck and Jan Rosenak research material dates from circa 1938-2003 and measures 17.6 linear feet. The collection contains correspondence, writings, notes, printed matter, tape-recorded interviews of artists, and photographs and slides of artists and artwork. The records document the Rosenak's research and collecting trips in the United States, often to isolated locales, in pursuit of new art and insights for their writing projects. The collection relates primarily to their research for Museum of American Folk Art Encyclopedia of Twentieth-Century American Folk Art and Artists, The People Speak: Navajo Folk Art, Contemporary American Folk Art: A Collector's Guide, The Saint Makers: Contemporary Santeras y Santeros, and are an important source of information on twentieth-century folk art.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 5 series:
Series 1: Research Files, circa 1938-1999 (Boxes 1-9, 19; 9.2 linear ft.)
Series 2: Loans to Exhibitions, circa 1991-1997, undated (Box 10; 0.4 linear ft.)
Series 3: Miscellaneous Files, circa 1969-2003 (Boxes 10-12; 2.0 linear ft.)
Series 4: Audiotaped Interviews of Artists, circa 1990s (Box 12-13; 1.5 linear ft.)
Series 5: Photographs and Slides, circa 1990s (Boxes 13-18; 4.5 linear ft.)
Provenance
The collection was donated by Chuck and Jan Rosenak, 1998-1999.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Use requires an appointment and is limited to the Washington, D.C. research facility.
Rosenak, Jan; Art -- Collectors and collecting; Artists -- New Mexico -- Interviews; Audiotapes; Folk art -- Southwest, New; Folk art -- United States; Folk artists -- United States; Interviews; Navajo Indians -- Art; Navajo Indians -- Social life and customs; Photographs; Santeros -- New Mexico -- Biography; Slides (photographs)
- Research Files, circa 1938 -1999; Series 1; (Boxes 1-9, 19; 9.2 linear ft.)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains research material used for the writing of four books by Chuck and Jan Rosenak: Museum of American Folk Art Encyclopedia of Twentieth-Century American Folk Art and Artists (New York: Abbeville, 1990), The People Speak: Navajo Folk Art (Flagstaff, Arizona: Northland Publishing, 1994), Contemporary American Fok Art: A Collector's Guide (New York: Abbeville, 1996), and The Saint Makers: Contemporary Santeras y Santeros (Flagstaff, Arizona: Northland Publishing, 1998). Records include correspondence, notes, writings and printed matter. See Series 4 and 5 for related audio and photgraphic materials.
  Arrangement note
  The series is arranged as 4 subseries, by publication:
  1.1: Museum of American Folk Art Encyclopedia of Twentieth-Century American Folk Art and Artists, circa 1942-1998
  1.2: The People Speak: Navajo Folk Art, circa 1938-1994
  1.3: Contemporary American Fok Art: A Collector's Guide, circa 1952-1997
  1.4: The Saint Makers: Contemporary Santeras y Santeros, circa 1988-1999
  - Museum of American Folk Art Encyclopedia of Twentieth-Century American Folk Art and Artists, circa 1942-1998; 1.1
    - Aaron, Jesse J., circa 1978-1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Abdulijaami, John, circa 1987-1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Aiken, Beverly ("Gayleen"), circa 1986-1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Alberts, Sylvia, circa 1989-1998 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Almon, Leroy, Sr., circa 1985-1997 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Alten, Fred, circa 1976-1998 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Ambrose, Ed, circa 1988-1996 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Anaya, Tobias, circa 1985-1998 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Archuleta, Felipe Benito, circa 1991-1997 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Archuleta, Leroy Ramon, circa 1993-1996 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Armstrong, Zebedee ("Z. B."), circa 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Ashby, Steven, circa 1977-1997 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
    - Aulisio, Joseph P., circa 1989-1998 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Badami, Andrea, circa 1970-1998 (Box 1, Folder 15-17)
    - Banks, John Willard, circa 1987-1998 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Bissonnette, Larry, circa 1980-1998 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Black, Calvin and Ruby, circa 1989-1998 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Black, Minnie, circa 1989-1998 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Blackmon, "Prophet" William J., circa 1986-1995 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Blayney, William Alvin, circa 1980-1993 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Blizzard, Georgia, circa 1979-1994 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Block, Andrew, circa 1989-1998 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Bochero (Besharo), Peter "Charlie", circa 1989-1998 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Boghosian, Nounoufar, circa 1971-1998 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Bogun, Reverend Maceptaw, circa 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Bond, Milton Wallace, circa 1992-1998 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Borkowski, Mary, circa 1982-1996 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Branchard, Emile, circa 1987-1998 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Brice, Bruce, circa 1987-1998 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Brito, Frank, circa 1987-1998 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Burnside, Richard, circa 1987-1998 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Burris, Bruce, circa 1991 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Burwell, Vernon, circa 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Butler, David, circa 1976-1998 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Carpenter, Miles Burkholder, circa 1989 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Cartledge, William ("Ned"), circa 1985-1994 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Childers, Russell, circa 1979-1991 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Church, Henry, circa 1987-1998 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Clark, Henry Ray, 1989-1996 (Box 1, Folder 42-43)
    - Coe, Clark W., circa 1983-1998 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Coins, Raymond, circa 1987-1998 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Colclough, ("Suh") Jim, circa 1979-1989 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Cooper, Jessie F. and Ronald E., circa 1987-1998 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Cordero, Helen, circa 1993 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Cornett, Chester, circa 1989-1998 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Cote, Adelard, circa 1989 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Coyle, Carlos Cortez, circa 1961-1989 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Craig, Burlon, circa 1989 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Crane, James, circa 1967-1989 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Cross, Abraham Lincoln, circa 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Cunningham, Earl, circa 1986-1996 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Darger, Henry J., circa 1987-1997 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Davis, Patrick, circa 1991-1996 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Davis, Ulysses, circa 1987-1998 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Davis, Vestie, circa 1969-1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Dey, John William ("Uncle Jack"), circa 1975-1998 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Dial, Thornton, Sr., circa 1993-1998 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Dieter, Charles, circa 1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Dinsmoor, Samuel Perry, circa 1976-1998 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Doriani, William, circa 1942-1998 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Drgac, Peter Paul ("Uncle Pete"), circa 1982-1998 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Edmondson, William, circa 1981-1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Erceg, Rose, circa 1987-1998 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Esteves, Antonio, circa 1982-1998 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Evans, Minnie, circa 1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Eyman, Earl, circa 1971-1998 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Fasanella, Ralph, circa 1972-1998; 1920 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Fellini, William (not in Encyclopedia), circa 1987-1998 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Felski, Albina, circa 1987-1998 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Fields, ("Cedar Creek") Charlie, circa 1987-1998 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Finster, Howard, circa 1980-1994 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
    - Flax Walter, circa 1974-1989 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Flanagan, Thomas Jefferson (not in Encyclopedia), circa 1987-1998 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Fracarossi, Joseph, circa 1977-1989 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Freeman, Claire (not in Encyclopedia), circa 1984-1989 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Frost, John Orne Johnson ("J.O.J") Frost, circa 1982-1998 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Furey, Joseph Endicott, circa 1989 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Gabriel, Romano, circa 1974-1989 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Garrett, Carlton Elonzo, circa 1979-1989 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Garrison, Harold, circa 1987-1998 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Gatto, Victor Joseph, circa 1977-1989 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Gibbs, Ezekiel, circa 1980-1992 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Gibson, Sybil, circa 1971-1995 (Box 2, Folder 30-32)
    - Gilkerson, Robert E., 1983-1992 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Godie, Lee, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Goodpaster, Denzil, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Gordon, Theodore, circa 1982-1997 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Griffin, Ralph, circa 1987-1998 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Gulick, Henry Thomas, circa 1987-1998 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Hamblett, Theora, circa 1987-1998 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Hamerman, Esther, circa 1987-1998 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Hampton, James, circa 1987-1998 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Hardin, Joseph, circa 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Harley, Steve, circa 1987-1998 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Harvey, Bessie, circa 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Hawkins, William Lawrence, circa 1987-1998 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Hayes, Reverend Herman Lee, circa 1987-1998 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Hewes, Clarence ("Charlie"), circa 1987-1998 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Hirshfield, Morris, circa 1987-1998 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Holley, Lonnie, circa 1987-1997 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Howard, Jessie, circa 1963-1998 (Box 2, Folder 50-51)
    - Hunter, Clementine, circa 1956-1998 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Jakobsen, Kathy, circa 1993 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Jennings, James Harold, circa 1987-1992 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Jones, Frank Albert, circa 1974-1991 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Jones, S.L. (Shields Landon), circa 1983-1991 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Kane, Andy, circa 1989-1993 (Box 2, Folder 57-58)
    - Kane, John, circa 1980's (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Kelley, Lavern, 1987-1993 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Kinney, Charley and Noah, circa 1980's-1998 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Kitchen, Tella, circa 1988-1998 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Kitchens, O. W. ("Pappy"), circa 1976-1989 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Klumpp, Gustav, circa 1971-1983 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Kozlowski, Karol, circa 1984 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Krans, Olof, circa 1981 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Layton, Elizabeth, circa 1983-1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Le Batard, Paul ("P"), circa 1987-1998 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Lebduska, Lawrence, circa 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Leedskalnin, Edward, circa 1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Levin, Abraham, circa 1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Lieberman, Harry, circa 1974-1991 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Light, Joe, circa 1984-1989 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Lopez, Jose Dolores and George, circa 1987-1998 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Lothrop, George Edwin, 1989; 1942 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Lucas, Charlie, circa 1987-1998 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Lunde, Emily, circa 1974-1998 (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
    - Maldonado, Alexander A., circa 1969-1988 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Marino, Robert J., circa 1970-1980's (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Martin, Eddie Owens ("St. Eom"), circa 1986-1997 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Martinez, Maria, circa 1979-1998 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Marzan, Gregorio, circa 1992-1997 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Massey, Willie, circa 1989-1998 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - McCarthy, Justin, circa 1979-1992 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - McCord, J. T. ("Jake"), circa 1987-1998 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - McDonald, Marjorie, circa 1984-1998 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - McKenzie, Carl, circa 1985-1998 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - McKillop, Edgar Alexander, circa 1987-1998 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Meaders, Quillian Lanier, circa 1989-1998 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Miller, Anna, circa 1946-1989 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Miller, R. A. Miller (not in Encyclopedia), 1991 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Minchell, Peter, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Mohamed, Ethel Wright ("Big Bamma"), 1976-1992 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Monza, Louis, circa 1960-1995 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Moran, Frank (not in Encyclopedia), circa 1959-1970 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Morgan, Ike, circa 1977-1990 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Morgan, Sister Gertrude, circa 1987-1998 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Moses, Anna Mary Robertson "Grandma", circa 1992 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Mumma, Eddy ("Mr. Eddy"), circa 1986-1993 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Murray, John ("J. B."), circa 1989 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Museum of American Folk Art: Current and On Show, circa 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 36-37)
    - Nampeyo, circa 1983-1991 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Naranjo, Louis, circa 1988-1997 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Odio, Saturnino Portuondo ("Pucho"), circa 1987-1998 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - O'Kelley, Mattie Lou, circa 1982-1997 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Orr, Georgianna, circa 1989-1992 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Owens, William ("W. C."), circa 1984-1998 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Palladino, Angela, circa 1987-1998 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Patton, Earnest, circa 1985-1990 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Payne, Leslie J., circa 1986-1991 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Perates, John W., circa 1987-1998 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Perkins, Reverend Benjamin ("B.F."), circa 1993 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Peterson, Oscar William ("Pelee"), circa 1987-1998 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Pickett, Joseph, circa 1987-1998 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Pierce, Elijah, circa 1972-1982 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Pippin, Horace, circa 1987-1998 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Pittman, Rosemary, circa 1987-1998 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Polk, Naomi ("Mrs. N. H."), circa 1987-1998 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Pressley, Daniel, circa 1969-1989 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Prisbrey, Tressa ("Grandma"), circa 1983-1997 (Box 3, Folder 56-57)
    - Pry, Lamont Alfred ("Old Ironsides"), circa 1988-1998 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Pugh, Loranzo Dow, circa 1990-1998 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Radoslovich, Matteo, circa 1987-1998 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Ramirez, Martin, circa 1963-1998 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Reed, Ernest ("Popeye"), circa 1976-1998 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Rendon, Enrique, circa 1986 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Riddle, Morton, circa 1987-1998 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Robertson, "Prophet" Royal, 1989-1993 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Roeder, John, circa 1962-1989 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Rogers, Juanita, circa 1981-1989 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Roseman, Bill, circa 1987-1998 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Salvatore, Anthony Joseph ("Tony Joe"), circa 1988-1994 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Sanchez, Mario, 1981-1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Sandoval, Alejandro ("Alex"), 1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Savitsky, Jack, circa 1965-1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Schmidt, Clarence, circa 1973-1991 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Schwob, Antoinette, circa 1987-1998 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Scott, James ("J. P."), circa 1990 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Shelley, Mary, circa 1987-1998 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Simpson, Vollis, circa 1987-1998 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Skyllas, Drossos P., circa 1987-1998 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Smith, Fred, circa 1969-1991 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Smith, Robert E., circa 1975-1998 (Box 4, Folder 13-14)
    - Sparrow, Simon, circa 1983-1994 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Spelce, Fannie Lou, circa 1972-1987 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Speller, Henry, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Sperger, Hugo, circa 1989 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Stinson, Lawrence, circa 1989-1994 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Stovall, "Queena", circa 1956-1998 (Box 4, Folder 20-21)
    - Stringfield, Clarence, circa 1970-1998 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Sudduth, Jimmy Lee, circa 1971-1990 (Box 4, Folder 23-24)
    - Sullivan, Patrick, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Swearingen, Reverend Johnnie, circa 1987-1998 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Taylor, Sarah Mary, circa 1987-1998 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Thomas, James Henry ("Son Ford"), circa 1989-1993 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Tolliver, Mose, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Tolson, Edgar and Donald Lee, circa 1997 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Turrell, Terry N., circa 1991-1998 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Valdez, Horacio, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Vigil, Manuel Vigil and Arthur ("Art"), circa 1986 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Virgous, Felix, circa 1990's (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Vivolo, John, circa 1987 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Von Bruenchenhein, Eugene, circa 1984-1996 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Walker, Inez Nathaniel, circa 1984-1996 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Ward, Velox, circa 1972 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Ward, William ("Wibb"), circa 1987-1998 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Warfel, Floretta Emma, circa 1987-1998 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Warmack, Gregory ("Mr. Imagination"), circa 1996 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Webster, Derek, circa 1982-1990 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Wentworth, Perley ("P. M."), circa 1987-1998 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Wernerus, Father Mathias, circa 1973-1993 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - White, George W., Jr., 1975 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - White, Willie, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Wiener, Isidor ("Pop" or "Grandpa"), circa 1987-1996 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Wilkerson, Lizzie, circa 1984-1989 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Wilkinson, Wallace ("Knox"), Jr., circa 1986-1998 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Willey, Philo Levi, circa 1978-1998 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Williams, George, circa 1987-1998 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Williamson, Clara ("Aunt Clara"), circa 1987-1998 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Willis, Luster, circa 1987-1998 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Yoakum, Joseph Elmer, circa 1985-1989 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Zahn, Albert, circa 1974-1998 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Zwirz, Jankiel ("Jack"), circa 1966-1992 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Miscellaneous info on new artists, circa 1958-1994 (Box 4, Folder 57-59)
    - Photographs, 1987-1998 (Box 5, Folder 1-5)
    - Copy of Museum of American Folk Art encyclopedia of Twentieth-Century American Folk Art and Artists (Annotated with Artist Signatures), 1990 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - The People Speak: Navajo Folk Art, circa 1938-1994; 1.2
    - Antonio, Johnson, circa 1981-1994 (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
    - Antonio, Sheila, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Arrowsmith, Rex, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Benally, Elise, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Beyale, Sandy, circa 1992-1994 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Buck, Delbert, circa 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Claw, Silas, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Cling, Alice, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Damon, Matilda, circa 1992-1994 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Deschillie, Mamie, circa 1991-1994 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Exhibition Clippings, circa 1987-1994 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Goodman, Louise Rose, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Greyeyes, Helen, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Growler, Ray, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Hot, Dan, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - John, Edith Herbert, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Kaye, Myra Tso, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Malone, Ronald, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Manygoats, Betty, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - McGee, Bruce, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - McHorse, Christine, circa 1989-1994 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Navajo Materials, circa 1991-1994 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Nez, Linda, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Pete, Fannie, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Peyote, circa 1938-1994 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Photographs, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Pioche, Dennis, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Planning Documents, circa 1991-1994 (Box 5, Folder 34-35)
    - Riggs, Florence, circa 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Sahmie, Ida, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Speeches, circa 1975-1985 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Tsihnahjinnie, Andrew, circa 1987-1994 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Tso, Faye, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Willeto, Harold and Robin, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Willeto, Leonard, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Yazzie, Tom, circa 1979-1994 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Yazzie, Wilford and Lulu, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Contemporary American Folk Art: A Collector's Guide, circa 1952-1997; 1.3
    - Adkins, Minnie and Garland, circa 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Amezcua, Consuelo ("Chelo") Gonzalez, circa 1968-1996 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Anderson, John, circa 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Anderson, Linda, circa 1996 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Anderson, Stephen Warde, circa 1990-1995 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Andrews, Alpha, circa 1986-1996 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Angel, Clyde, circa 1994 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Arning, Eddie, circa 1985-1994 (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
    - Baker, Thomas King, circa 1963-1995 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Barker, Linvel, circa 1991 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Barnes, Ricky, circa 1996 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Bauer, Jim, circa 1993 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Bell, Ralph, circa 1984-1993 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Billiot, Ivy, circa 1996 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Billups, Patsy, circa 1994 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Birnbaum, Aaron, circa 1996 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Bolden, Hawkins, circa 1996 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Bostic, Rudolph Valentino, circa 1994 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Boudreaux, A. J. ("Sainte-James Boudrôt"), circa 1996 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Bowlin, Loy A. ("Rhinestone Cowboy"), circa 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Brown, Russell ("Smokey"), circa 1991-1993 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Bruno, Frank, circa 1968-1994 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Butler, Edward, circa 1996 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Byron, Archie, circa 1988-1994 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Cahill, Duke, circa 1996 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Chavoya, Raymond, circa 1996 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Clark, Larry, circa 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Clawson, Rex, circa 1963- 1996 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Coker, Jerry W., circa 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Crawford, Reece, circa 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Crocker, Michael, circa 1990-1994 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Crowell, Harold, circa 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Cruz, Pearline, circa 1994 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Dahvah, Yahrah, circa 1994 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Dawson, William, circa 1988-1990 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - DePrie, Gerald ("Creative"), circa 1994 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Dixon, Carl, circa 1994 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Doman, Eileen, circa 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Dowdall, Brian, circa 1994-1996 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Doyle, Sam ("Uncle Sam"), circa 1986-1989 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Dulaney, Burgess, circa 1996 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Ellis, John Robert, circa 1996 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Evans, Minnie, circa 1969-1992 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Farmer, Josephus, circa 1982-1989 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Ferdinand, Roy, Jr., circa 1994 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Finster,Howard and Family, circa 1986-1994 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Gerdes, John, circa 1986-1994 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Gibson, Evelyn, circa 1988 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Gibson, Sybil, circa 1992 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Godie, Lee ("Baglady"), circa 1982-1994 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Green, Homer, circa 1996 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Grgich, Anne, circa 1993-1996 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Grimes, Ken, circa 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Halozan, Bertha A., circa 1966-1993 (Box 7, Folder 4)